<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Command Line Erico</title><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/index.html</link>
<description>This is where I post things, from command line</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 22:22:28 -0300</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 22:22:28 -0300</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Having fun with a home server
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Recently I decided to use a spare d525mw Intel board I had to build a small home server.
This board has soldered, fanless, atom dual core processor soldered on it, I'm running it
with 4GB RAM and an old Samsung 500GB HDD. </p>

<p>For the OS, I decided to use Ubuntu Server 15.10. Installing was a bit of a challenge because I have
no monitors and had disabled USB boot a long time ago, so my solution was to lend a monitor just 
for the install proccess. In the meantime I learned about preseeding, which was fun and a good idea
on how to install an OS on it in the future - the board has no hdmi.</p>

<h2>Using a home server</h2>

<p>So what good can a home server do? Well, right now, aside from using it as a learning tool I'm 
using to run a Twitter Bot I made, Transmission for torrenting things (web controlled) and 
Owncloud. Owncloud was a bit of pain to setup, but it's working well right now. I plan to install
Plex for video streaming, mpd for audio streaming (and also playing audio on it as a radio).</p>

<p>The server is 3 days old, so I will update more on this in the future. If you want to see my Twitter
bot, it's available, along with a nice install script and guide, on 
https://github.com/ericoporto/Chove-Agora</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_home-server.html'>home-server</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/having-fun-with-a-home-server.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./having-fun-with-a-home-server.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 22:10:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Using Pandoc as a Markdown to Docx converter
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So, I don't really like Word. But it's nearly unavoidable, 
especially in office environment (see what I did here?).</p>

<p>Word has some good things, it can be read and edited by most
people and can be easily converted to Kindle format. </p>

<p>So the command line:</p>

<pre><code>pandoc -o output.docx -f markdown -t docx input.md
</code></pre>

<p>Tadah! And if you are in Windows right now, one good thing is
that you can run pandoc without installing - doesn't require being
admin! <a href="
https://gist.github.com/ericoporto/ccf9547d9e4d0786113c">Also I've made a <code>.bat</code> for making this easier in Windows</a>. The bat
in action below: </p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/2244442/13187576/16cd68bc-d733-11e5-8629-802042f7bda6.gif" alt="drag and drop" title="" /></p>

<p>If you need help writing markdown, <a href="https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet">here is a cheatsheet</a>!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/using-pandoc-as-a-markdown-to-docx-converter.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./using-pandoc-as-a-markdown-to-docx-converter.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 22:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
How to configure keyboard on Crunchbang
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So this blog is written from my Old EEEPC 701 with 4G SSD. 
I used to run a exotic Gentoo until I've been away from it for 4 months and 
forget how to use it. So I've tried some distros and all and really like Crunchbang!</p>

<p>But it ended, so now I'm using whatever I can use until everything require or too much maintenance
or too much everything. I like this netbook, it was donated to me and I like to keep using it.</p>

<p>Enough, let's get to the keyboard part. Basically you need to edit the keyboard file:</p>

<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/default/keyboard
</code></pre>

<p>And if your keyboard is us intl, modify the file like this:</p>

<pre><code># KEYBOARD CONFIGURATION FILE

# Consult the keyboard(5) manual page.

XKBMODEL="pc105"
XKBLAYOUT="us"
XKBVARIANT="intl"
XKBOPTIONS=""

BACKSPACE="guess"
</code></pre>

<p>Then restart and everything should work! 
This assumes you have the package <code>keyboard-configuration</code> installed.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_troubleshooting.html'>troubleshooting</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/how-to-configure-keyboard-on-crunchbang.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./how-to-configure-keyboard-on-crunchbang.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 22:00:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cool Command Line Tools
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So today I want to talk about the cool command line tools available today to make
your life living in the terminal easier!</p>

<h2>Nano</h2>

<p>This is old, but if you need a fast and quick text editor for not too long texts, this is 
what you want. For short texts, this is it!</p>

<h2>Slap Editor</h2>

<p>If you need to edit code, this is the closest to Sublime Text / Atom you will get on terminal.</p>

<p>It requires nodejs and npm installed. But having then and a internet connection will lead us
to the next one in this list...</p>

<h2>how2</h2>

<p>How2 is Google+Stackoverflow without needing to leave the confy place that is the terminal. 
It's really good for finding help using intuitive commands.</p>

<p>And that's it for today!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/cool-command-line-tools.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./cool-command-line-tools.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 19:50:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Hello World
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is a test post, the first post from the <strong>bashblog</strong> script!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_hello-world.html'>hello-world</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/hello-world.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./hello-world.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:04:00 -0300</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
