<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Command Line Erico</title><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/index.html</link>
<description>This is where I post things, from command line</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 21:00:17 -0300</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 21:00:17 -0300</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
How to stream audio from Ubuntu to DLNA device
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/JKgUibW.png" alt="pulseaudio-dlna on ubuntu" title=""></p>

<p>Today I wanted to stream the audio from my ubuntu 16.04 to a dlna device. I had to install from the git source instead of the ppa because I had a conflict with chardet package in my system. the error was <i>"error: chardet 2.3.0 is installed" but chardet<3.1.0,>=3.0.2 is required by set(['requests'])</i>.
</p>

<p>here are my commands to install <b>pulseaudio-dlna</b>:</p>

<pre><code>cd ~
pip install chardet
mkdir pulseaudio-dlna
cd pulseaudio-dlna/
git clone git@github.com:masmu/pulseaudio-dlna.git
virtualenv --system-site-packages .
source bin/activate
cd pulseaudio-dlna/
pip install .
pulseaudio-dlna &
</code></pre>

<p>You can create a script to start the pulseaudio-dlna when the computer starts. You can get more info about <a href="https://github.com/masmu/pulseaudio-dlna">pulseaudio-dlna in the repository</a>.  </p>

<p>If you need a dlna device to test, you can install <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bubblesoft.android.bubbleupnp&hl=en">Bubble UPNP</a> on your Android device and have it as a remote sound sink.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_dlna.html'>dlna</a>, <a href='tag_pulseaudio.html'>pulseaudio</a>, <a href='tag_sound.html'>sound</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/how-to-stream-audio-from-ubuntu-to-dlna-device.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./how-to-stream-audio-from-ubuntu-to-dlna-device.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 21:00:09 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
On History and VIM
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The command line is an effective way of getting things done. 
One of the things I like the most is how obvious are the tasks
that deserves being automated by just running the <code>history</code> command
and checking what you do most. </p>

<p>I did some adjustments in my history, like making it twice as big as
default settings in Ubuntu. I operate the history a lot, mostly with 
<code>ctrl+r</code> in bash, and then I can use my brain to remember other things. 
When I am lazy I throw some <code>history | grep command I don't remember parameters</code>, 
<code>pandoc</code> and <code>tar</code> are good examples. Some git magic I usually anotate 
as a gist in github since I have a haystack of git commands in my 
history.</p>

<p>The thing about history is that once you deal with a lot, you
eventually will fall into having carefully written bash scripts that
make your work easier - like publishing a python lib to Python Package 
Index.</p>

<p>And while you are at the command line, I really recommend you to learn
<strong>vim</strong>, it's an awesome text editor that can be extended with many plugins.
My favorite right now is ZenRoom2, that can be called by typing <code>:Goyo</code>,
it will give you a confortable place to write texts distraction free.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_VIM.html'>VIM</a>, <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/on-history-and-vim.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./on-history-and-vim.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Using Pandoc as a Markdown to Docx converter
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So, I don't really like Word. But it's nearly unavoidable, 
especially in office environment (see what I did here?).</p>

<p>Word has some good things, it can be read and edited by most
people and can be easily converted to Kindle format. </p>

<p>So the command line:</p>

<pre><code>pandoc -o output.docx -f markdown -t docx input.md
</code></pre>

<p>Tadah! And if you are in Windows right now, one good thing is
that you can run pandoc without installing - doesn't require being
admin! <a href="
https://gist.github.com/ericoporto/ccf9547d9e4d0786113c">Also I've made a <code>.bat</code> for making this easier in Windows</a>. The bat
in action below: </p>

<p><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/2244442/13187576/16cd68bc-d733-11e5-8629-802042f7bda6.gif" alt="drag and drop" title="" /></p>

<p>If you need help writing markdown, <a href="https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet">here is a cheatsheet</a>!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/using-pandoc-as-a-markdown-to-docx-converter.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./using-pandoc-as-a-markdown-to-docx-converter.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Downloading subtitles by the command line
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Today I want to show you guys the awesome tool that's 
<a href="https://github.com/Diaoul/subliminal">Subliminal, by Diaoul</a>. Subliminal allow you to download a
subtitle for a downloaded series or movie by using the command line (did you bought Angry Video 
Game Nerd or PHD Movie and was surprised it had no subtitles in your language?).</p>

<p>First you have to install it. Assuming you have pip and python on your system:</p>

<pre><code>sudo pip install -U subliminal
</code></pre>

<p>After the instalation, you can use the follow command from command line to download a 
subtitle (I'm going to use brazilian portuguese):</p>

<pre><code>subliminal download -l pt-BR movie-filename.extension
</code></pre>

<p>And that's it! Use <code>-l en</code> for english subtitles. The software also has a Nautilus extension that
gives cool right click subtitle download for movie files - you can check on the project's webpage
on github.</p>

<p>I just use the command line, right now trying to bake a script to automate subtitle downloading. </p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/downloading-subtitles-by-the-command-line.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./downloading-subtitles-by-the-command-line.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Having fun with a home server
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Recently I decided to use a spare d525mw Intel board I had to build a small home server.
This board has soldered, fanless, atom dual core processor soldered on it, I'm running it
with 4GB RAM and an old Samsung 500GB HDD. </p>

<p>For the OS, I decided to use Ubuntu Server 15.10. Installing was a bit of a challenge because I have
no monitors and had disabled USB boot a long time ago, so my solution was to lend a monitor just 
for the install proccess. In the meantime I learned about preseeding, which was fun and a good idea
on how to install an OS on it in the future - the board has no hdmi.</p>

<h2>Using a home server</h2>

<p>So what good can a home server do? Well, right now, aside from using it as a learning tool I'm 
using to run a Twitter Bot I made, Transmission for torrenting things (web controlled) and 
Owncloud. Owncloud was a bit of pain to setup, but it's working well right now. I plan to install
Plex for video streaming, mpd for audio streaming (and also playing audio on it as a radio).</p>

<p>The server is 3 days old, so I will update more on this in the future. If you want to see my Twitter
bot, it's available, along with a nice install script and guide, on 
<a href="https://github.com/ericoporto/Chove-Agora">Chove Agora github page</a>.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_home-server.html'>home-server</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/having-fun-with-a-home-server.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./having-fun-with-a-home-server.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Hello World
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is a test post, the first post from the <strong>bashblog</strong> script!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_hello-world.html'>hello-world</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/hello-world.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./hello-world.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
How to configure keyboard on Crunchbang
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So this blog is written from my Old EEEPC 701 with 4G SSD. 
I used to run a exotic Gentoo until I've been away from it for 4 months and 
forget how to use it. So I've tried some distros and all and really like Crunchbang!</p>

<p>But it ended, so now I'm using whatever I can use until everything require or too much maintenance
or too much everything. I like this netbook, it was donated to me and I like to keep using it.</p>

<p>Enough, let's get to the keyboard part. Basically you need to edit the keyboard file:</p>

<pre><code>sudo nano /etc/default/keyboard
</code></pre>

<p>And if your keyboard is us intl, modify the file like this:</p>

<pre><code># KEYBOARD CONFIGURATION FILE

# Consult the keyboard(5) manual page.

XKBMODEL="pc105"
XKBLAYOUT="us"
XKBVARIANT="intl"
XKBOPTIONS=""

BACKSPACE="guess"
</code></pre>

<p>Then restart and everything should work! 
This assumes you have the package <code>keyboard-configuration</code> installed.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_troubleshooting.html'>troubleshooting</a></p>


<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/how-to-configure-keyboard-on-crunchbang.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./how-to-configure-keyboard-on-crunchbang.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
How to fork your own repository on Github
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Recently I had to fork my own repository on Github and looked through the web.
I ended up taking the solution from a comment in a website that suggested a much complex approach.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>create a new repository in Github, don't add a readme or anything.</p></li>
<li><p>clone it on your computer</p></li>
<li><p>add the original repository (the one you want to fork) as upstream source.</p>

<p><code>git remote add upstream [url]</code></p></li>
<li><p>fetch and merge upstream.</p>

<p><code>git fetch upstream &amp; git merge upstream/master</code></p></li>
</ol>

<p>Thanks to Mark Marijnissen.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_github.html'>github</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/how-to-fork-your-own-repository-on-github.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./how-to-fork-your-own-repository-on-github.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cool Command Line Tools
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>So today I want to talk about the cool command line tools available today to make
your life living in the terminal easier!</p>

<h2>Nano</h2>

<p>This is old, but if you need a fast and quick text editor for not too long texts, this is 
what you want. For short texts, this is it!</p>

<h2>Slap Editor</h2>

<p>If you need to edit code, this is the closest to Sublime Text / Atom you will get on terminal.</p>

<p>It requires nodejs and npm installed. But having then and a internet connection will lead us
to the next one in this list...</p>

<h2>how2</h2>

<p>How2 is Google+Stackoverflow without needing to leave the confy place that is the terminal. 
It's really good for finding help using intuitive commands.</p>

<p>And that's it for today!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_command-line-tools.html'>command-line-tools</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/cool-command-line-tools.html</link>
<guid>http://ericoporto.github.io/bashblog/./cool-command-line-tools.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Erico Porto</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:39:56 -0300</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
